<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/css' href='file:/C:/Users/nchun/AppData/Local/Programs/Oxygen XML Editor 21/frameworks/dita/DITA-OT3.x/plugins/com.oxygenxml.webhelp.responsive/oxygen-webhelp/app/topic-page-print.css'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/css' href='file:/C:/Users/nchun/AppData/Local/Programs/Oxygen XML Editor 21/frameworks/dita/css/print/p-dita.css'?>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/css' href='file:/C:/Users/nchun/AppData/Local/Programs/Oxygen XML Editor 21/frameworks/dita/DITA-OT3.x/plugins/com.oxygenxml.editlink/pdf-css.css'?>
<map xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
    xmlns:opentopic-index="http://www.idiominc.com/opentopic/index"
    xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
    xmlns:oxy="http://www.oxygenxml.com/extensions/author"
    xmlns:nd="http://www.oxygenxml.com/css2fo/named-destinations"
    xmlns:opentopic="http://www.idiominc.com/opentopic"
    xmlns:css2fo="http://www.oxygenxml.com/css2fo"
    xmlns:dita-ot="dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" cascade="merge" class="- map/map "
    ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
    domains="(map mapgroup-d) (topic abbrev-d) (topic delay-d) a(props deliveryTarget) (map ditavalref-d) (map glossref-d) (topic hazard-d) (topic hi-d) (topic indexing-d) (topic markup-d) (topic pr-d) (topic relmgmt-d) (topic sw-d) (topic ui-d) (topic ut-d) (topic markup-d xml-d)"
    xtrc="map:1;3:6"
    xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/index.ditamap">
    <oxy:front-page class="- front-page/front-page ">
        <oxy:front-page-title class="- front-page/front-page-title ">
            <title xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot"
                xmlns:ot-placeholder="http://suite-sol.com/namespaces/ot-placeholder"
                class="- topic/title ">My Visit to Dancing Rabbit Ecovillage</title>
        </oxy:front-page-title>
    </oxy:front-page>
    <opentopic:map xmlns:ot-placeholder="http://suite-sol.com/namespaces/ot-placeholder"
        class="- toc/toc ">
        <oxy:toc-title class="- toc/title " empty="true"/>
        <title xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot"
            class="- topic/title ">My Visit to Dancing Rabbit Ecovillage</title>
        <topicref xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" is-chapter="true"
            class="- map/topicref " href="#unique_1" type="concept">
            <topicmeta class="- map/topicmeta " data-topic-id="concept_w1g_qpv_phb">
                <resourceid appid="concept_w1g_qpv_phb" class="- topic/resourceid "
                    oxy-source="topic"/>
                <navtitle href="#unique_1" class="- topic/navtitle ">Introduction</navtitle>
                <?ditaot gentext?>
                <?ditaot genshortdesc?>
                <shortdesc class="- map/shortdesc ">Introduction about my reason for visiting
                    Dancing Rabbit</shortdesc>
            </topicmeta>
        </topicref>
        <topicref xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" is-chapter="true"
            class="- map/topicref " href="#unique_2" type="concept">
            <topicmeta class="- map/topicmeta " data-topic-id="concept_llv_ppv_phb">
                <resourceid appid="concept_llv_ppv_phb" class="- topic/resourceid "
                    oxy-source="topic"/>
                <navtitle href="#unique_2" class="- topic/navtitle ">A Quick Overview of Dancing
                    Rabbit</navtitle>
                <?ditaot gentext?>
            </topicmeta>
        </topicref>
        <topicref xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" is-chapter="true"
            class="- map/topicref " href="#unique_3" type="concept">
            <topicmeta class="- map/topicmeta " data-topic-id="concept_lwq_15x_nhb">
                <resourceid appid="concept_lwq_15x_nhb" class="- topic/resourceid "
                    oxy-source="topic"/>
                <navtitle href="#unique_3" class="- topic/navtitle ">Infrastructure and
                    Zoning</navtitle>
                <?ditaot gentext?>
            </topicmeta>
        </topicref>
    </opentopic:map>
    <concept xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" break-before="true"
        is-chapter="true" oxy:topicref-class="- map/topicref "
        class="- topic/topic concept/concept " id="unique_1" nd:nd-id="concept_w1g_qpv_phb"
        oid="concept_w1g_qpv_phb">
        <title class="- topic/title ">Introduction</title>
        <shortdesc class="- topic/shortdesc ">Introduction about my reason for visiting Dancing
            Rabbit</shortdesc>
        <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
            <p class="- topic/p ">Hoping to discover the simple life in a sustainable utopia, I
                visited a few ecovillages over the years, starting with my visit to Dancing Rabbit
                Ecovillage (DR for short) during the summer of 2012. Ecovillages are intentional
                communities with a focus on ecological sustainability. Having been interested in
                sustainability and alternative lifestyles for some time while working in technology
                companies, I initially thought about becoming a farmer and volunteered at a few
                organic farms until I realized how difficult farming is. I shifted my focus to
                looking for sustainable communities and learned about DR on the Internet. DR is an
                ecovillage in Rutledge, MO that set itself apart from the mainstream by locally
                generating electricity from renewable sources, using composting toilets, building
                houses with natural materials, reducing fossil fuel consumption, and focusing on
                forming a close-knit community. For a period of two weeks from June 25th to July 9th
                of 2012, I lived at DR to participate in its visitor program for prospective
                residents. As a part of the program, we also visited Sandhill Farm, a small
                income-sharing community in the same town for a day. Immediately after my two-week
                visit, I stayed for two days in DR's sister village Red Earth Farms. In September of
                2015, I visited two more ecovillages, spending one week at Earthaven Ecovillage in
                Black Mountain, NC and just one day at Sirius Community. </p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">While the visit to various ecovillages showed me inspiring ways to
                re-design our neighborhoods and our day-to-day lives, I also realized that the
                simple life is not so simple, and starting newsustainable villages from scratch is
                an impractical solution on a massive scale. Since I stayed at Dancing Rabbit the
                longest out of the four ecovillages I visited, I decided to write an essay about it.
                Another reason for focusing on DR over other ecovillages is that I had the most
                favorable impression of DR out of all the ecovillages I visited. I occasionally talk
                about in other ecovillages in this essay to compare them against Dancing Rabbit.</p>
        </conbody>
    </concept>
    <concept xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" break-before="true"
        is-chapter="true" oxy:topicref-class="- map/topicref "
        class="- topic/topic concept/concept " id="unique_2" nd:nd-id="concept_llv_ppv_phb"
        oid="concept_llv_ppv_phb">
        <title class="- topic/title ">A Quick Overview of Dancing Rabbit</title>
        <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
            <p class="- topic/p ">Dancing Rabbit is an ecovillage located on the outskirts of
                Rutledge, a tiny town in a rural part of northeast Missouri. The main town center of
                Rutledge is about two miles away from DR and had 109 people according to the town
                sign when I visited DR. DR itself had about 55 members and residents - these two
                roles have some distinct differences explained in "Becoming a Member" section - and
                15 children, so the total added up to 70. I also counted about 20 visitors and
                wexers, or work exchangers. Work exchangers provided labor to the host families in
                exchange for free food and loedging. While the population of DR sounded small, it
                seemed to be one of the largest and oldest surviving ecovillages in the United
                States based on my quick research.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">In 1997, a group of idealistic people, many from the West Coast,
                founded Dancing Rabbit as an ecovillage to explore more sustainable ways of living.
                They were looking for a place with inexpensive real estate and other conditions
                suitable to starting an intentional community, and Rutledge was a good fit. What
                helped the move was that Sandhill Farm, another intentional community, was already
                established a few miles away.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">DR is composed of multiple legal entities, including the
                educational nonprofit arm and DR Land Trust. DR Land Trust owns about 277 acres of
                real estate with four acres of it more heavily developed as the main part of the
                town. The rest of the land consists of undeveloped prairies, forests, a large
                swimming pond, and 20 acres that got opened up for farming in 2012 before my
                visit.</p>
        </conbody>
    </concept>
    <concept xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot" break-before="true"
        is-chapter="true" oxy:topicref-class="- map/topicref "
        class="- topic/topic concept/concept " id="unique_3" nd:nd-id="concept_lwq_15x_nhb"
        oid="concept_lwq_15x_nhb">
        <title class="- topic/title ">Infrastructure and Zoning</title>
        <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
            <p class="- topic/p ">The interesting infrastructure feature at DR, which would turn out
                to be a common feature in all ecovillages I visited except for Red Earth Farms, was
                the common house. The common house at DR was a large, multi-purpose building with
                plastered straw bale walls. People used the large living room for meetings,
                activities, and dining. The bathroom area had multiple composting toilets, two
                showers, and a few energy-efficient laundry machines but no dryers. People dried all
                their clothes in the sun using clotheslines.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">For intentional communities, a central community building where
                people can easily get together on a daily basis is essential in order to facilitate
                communication and coordination. It also serves as a no-cost social space with a
                roof, which is a refreshing departure from mainstream communities that tend to only
                have commercial third places like cafes. While most cities have libraries as third
                places free and open to the public, the main function of libraries is quiet learning
                and research, not social interaction. Experiencing the common house at ecovillages
                made me wonder how practical it would be to implement such places in mainstream
                cities.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">The common house had some deficiencies that hinted at DR's slow
                group decision-making process. Despite the village being about 15 years-old by 2012,
                the common house did not have thermal curtains while pretty much all individual
                homes did. Many people I met at DR said that changes can happen very slowly at DR.
                It seemed more accurate to say people were fast at making decisions on individual
                matters but slow on group matters. Since the common house was very uncomfortable
                during hot weather, many people without a permanent home, mostly new residents,
                visitors, and work exchangers, went to the bar at the Milkweed Mercantile, the
                swimming pond, or Zimmerman's general store in Rutledge town center.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">Rutledge and the surrounding areas had enough infrastructure for
                basic goods and services. The town center of Rutledge, about two miles away from DR,
                had an impressive general store named Zimmerman's, or Zimmy's, as it was
                affectionately called. The store had a small cafe that sold burgers and ice cream.
                People from DR would come to Zimmy's and spend a few hours just chatting and
                enjoying the cool AC breeze. About 12 miles away from DR was a bigger town named
                Memphis, equipped with a supermarket, a library, a department store, and even a
                local theater company.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">DR had relatively dense zoning for a rural town where some
                buildings were as close as 5 yards from each other. Houses tended to have small
                yards suitable for gardening while lacking a driveway following the DR's ban on
                using automobiles within the village. DR's town structure was based on what members
                called the “European model”: Homes were clustered together in a dense central area
                while a large area of farmland surrounded the central area. This structure allowed
                for more frequent social interaction and cooperation at the expense of not being
                able to constantly monitor the farmland.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">Not content with this model, a group of former members formed the
                sister village of Red Earth Farms about a mile from DR. Former members who wanted to
                focus more on homesteading structured Red Earth Farms based on what they called the
                “American model” - each individual house was surrounded by a large ring of farmland,
                which allowed each household a direct view and access to the farmland. At the time
                of my visit, Red Earth Farms had what I remember to be four households. Rather than
                having a more strict ecological covenant like Dancing Rabbit, Red Earth held annual
                ecological audits to see how they were doing and what they could do better next
                year. Similar to DR, Red Earth Farms also had a central parking lot at the edge of
                the village, but it had no central common house. The houses were so spread out that
                it took several minutes to walk from the central parking lot to the nearest house
                while at DR, it took only a minute or so to walk from the parking lot to the nearest
                house. Although DR and Red Earth Farms were technically two separate sister
                villages, they often functioned as one with villagers frequently visiting each
                other. People from Red Earth Farms would often walk for a mile to come to DR
                community events. The following is a conceptual diagram showing the town layouts of
                DR and Red Earth Farms.</p>
            <p class="- topic/p ">
                <image align="center" class="- topic/image "
                    href="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/images/ecovillage%20layouts.png"
                    id="unique_3_Connect_42_image_ydv_rwv_phb" nd:nd-id="image_ydv_rwv_phb"
                    placement="break" scalefit="yes">
                    <alt class="- topic/alt ">A conceptual diagram showing the layout of Dancing
                        Rabbit on the left and the layout of Red Earth Farms on the right. Dancing
                        Rabbit has a common house and resident houses clustered closely together
                        surrounded by a ring of farmland. Red Earth Farms has houses spread out, and
                        each house is surrounded by a ring of farmland.</alt>
                </image>
            </p>
        </conbody>
    </concept>
</map>
