<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<concept xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
    xmlns:dita-ot="http://dita-ot.sourceforge.net/ns/201007/dita-ot"
    xmlns:opentopic-index="http://www.idiominc.com/opentopic/index"
    class="- topic/topic concept/concept " ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
    domains="(topic concept) (topic abbrev-d) a(props deliveryTarget) (topic equation-d) (topic hazard-d) (topic hi-d) (topic indexing-d) (topic markup-d) (topic mathml-d) (topic pr-d) (topic relmgmt-d) (topic sw-d) (topic svg-d) (topic ui-d) (topic ut-d) (topic markup-d xml-d)"
    id="concept_lwq_15x_nhb" xtrc="concept:1;3:35"
    xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita">
    <title class="- topic/title " xtrc="title:1;4:12"
        xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
        >Infrastructure and Zoning</title>
    <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody " xtrc="conbody:1;5:14"
        xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita">
        <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:1;6:12"
            xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
            >The interesting infrastructure feature at DR, which would turn out to be a common
            feature in all ecovillages I visited except for Red Earth Farms, was the common house.
            The common house at DR was a large, multi-purpose building with plastered straw bale
            walls. People used the large living room for meetings, activities, and dining. The
            bathroom area had multiple composting toilets, two showers, and a few energy-efficient
            laundry machines but no dryers. People dried all their clothes in the sun using
            clotheslines.</p>
        <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:2;13:12"
            xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
            >For intentional communities, a central community building where people can easily get
            together on a daily basis is essential in order to facilitate communication and
            coordination. It also serves as a no-cost social space with a roof, which is a
            refreshing departure from mainstream communities that tend to only have commercial third
            places like cafes. While most cities have libraries as third places free and open to the
            public, the main function of libraries is quiet learning and research, not social
            interaction. Experiencing the common house at ecovillages made me wonder how practical
            it would be to implement such places in mainstream cities.</p>
        <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:3;21:12"
            xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
            >The common house had some deficiencies that hinted at DR's slow group decision-making
            process. Despite the village being about 15 years-old by 2012, the common house did not
            have thermal curtains while pretty much all individual homes did. Many people I met at
            DR said that changes can happen very slowly at DR. It seemed more accurate to say people
            were fast at making decisions on individual matters but slow on group matters. Since the
            common house was very uncomfortable during hot weather, many people without a permanent
            home, mostly new residents, visitors, and work exchangers, went to the bar at the
            Milkweed Mercantile, the swimming pond, or Zimmerman's general store in Rutledge town
            center.</p>
        <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:4;30:12"
            xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
            >Rutledge and the surrounding areas had enough infrastructure for basic goods and
            services. The town center of Rutledge, about two miles away from DR, had an impressive
            general store named Zimmerman's, or Zimmy's, as it was affectionately called. The store
            had a small cafe that sold burgers and ice cream. People from DR would come to Zimmy's
            and spend a few hours just chatting and enjoying the cool AC breeze. About 12 miles away
            from DR was a bigger town named Memphis, equipped with a supermarket, a library, a
            department store, and even a local theater company.</p>
        <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:5;37:12"
            xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
            >DR had relatively dense zoning for a rural town where some buildings were as close as 5
            yards from each other. Houses tended to have small yards suitable for gardening while
            lacking a driveway following the DR's ban on using automobiles within the village. DR's
            town structure was based on what members called the “European model”: Homes were
            clustered together in a dense central area while a large area of farmland surrounded the
            central area. This structure allowed for more frequent social interaction and
            cooperation at the expense of not being able to constantly monitor the farmland.</p>
        <p class="- topic/p " xtrc="p:6;44:12"
            xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
            >Not content with this model, a group of former members formed the sister village of Red
            Earth Farms about a mile from DR. Former members who wanted to focus more on
            homesteading structured Red Earth Farms based on what they called the “American model” -
            each individual house was surrounded by a large ring of farmland, which allowed each
            household a direct view and access to the farmland. At the time of my visit, Red Earth
            Farms had what I remember to be four households. Rather than having a more strict
            ecological covenant like Dancing Rabbit, Red Earth held annual ecological audits to see
            how they were doing and what they could do better next year. Similar to DR, Red Earth
            Farms also had a central parking lot at the edge of the village, but it had no central
            common house. The houses were so spread out that it took several minutes to walk from
            the central parking lot to the nearest house while at DR, it took only a minute or so to
            walk from the parking lot to the nearest house. Although DR and Red Earth Farms were
            technically two separate sister villages, they often functioned as one with villagers
            frequently visiting each other. People from Red Earth Farms would often walk for a mile
            to come to DR community events. The following is a conceptual diagram showing the town
            layouts of DR and Red Earth Farms.<image class="- topic/image "
                href="images/ecovillage%20layouts.png" id="image_ydv_rwv_phb" placement="inline"
                width="100" xtrc="image:1;60:41"
                xtrf="file:/C:/Users/nchun/GitHub/visiting_dancing_rabbit_ecovillage/infra_and_zoning.dita"
            /></p>
    </conbody>
    <opentopic-index:index.groups/>
</concept>
